Wilton Historical Society Printed Matter Collection
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
Wilton Historical Society Printed Matter Collection
Circa 1800-2013
Wilton Historical Society (Wilton, Conn.)
PM
17 linear feet; 5 drawers
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
The Wilton Historical Society Printed Matter Collection contains a wide range of printed matter relating to Wilton history, including pamphlets, almanacs, reports, and innumerable other publication types. Likewise, the topical scope of the collection is broad. The earliest original items date to the early to mid-1800s, although later reprints of even earlier materials are included. The bulk of the collection was produced in the twentieth century.
Restrictions
Collection open for research.
History
1. Wilton Historical Society Printed Matter Collection
The Wilton Historical Society, founded in 1938, has compiled this extensive collection of printed matter pertaining to Wilton and its residents. Additions have been made by Carol Russell, Wilton Historical Society Archivist and Wilton Town Historian. The intellectual content of the majority of the materials in this collection was created in Wilton by local residents, businesses, churches, clubs, societies, and government institutions; the actual printing of collection materials, on the other hand, was done variously in Wilton, Norwalk, or further afield.
2. Wilton History Room
The Wilton History Room is a unique collaboration between the Wilton Historical Society (WHS) and the Wilton Library Association (WLA). Compiled beginning in 1938, the archival collections of the Wilton Historical Society had been stored in the 18th century Fitch House. In 1980, the officers and trustees of the WHS, in conversation with the director and board members of the WLA, determined that a climate controlled space, improved organization, and better public accessibility were necessary; and so in January 1984 they established a home for the collection in the Wilton Library. Organization of the collections was supported by the Cudlipp Memorial Fund and undertaken by Carol Russell. The Wilton Historical Society has retained its ownership, while the Wilton Library maintains the collections, and provides access and assistance to patrons.
The Wilton History Room is one of the most complete, organized, and well-staffed historical research facilities, for a town of our size, in Fairfield County. It is supported by the WHS, the WLA, The Russell Fund, The History Room Fund, local non-profit organizations, individual donors, and community volunteers.
Today, the original archival collections of the WHS take up half of the Wilton History Room. Another quarter are library items. The collected papers of local organizations comprise the remainder: Cannon Grange, Children's Theater, Daughters of the American Revolution, Hurlbutt Street School House Association, Kiwanis Club, League of Women Voters, Rotary Club, Town Association, Weir Farm Stewardship Committee, Wilton Garden Club, Wilton Land Conservation Trust, Wilton Library, Wilton Playshop, Wilton Woman's Club, and more.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Wilton Historical Society Printed Matter Collection contains advertisements, almanacs, annual reports, calendars, directories, greeting and post cards, guidebooks and real estate brochures, newsletters and bulletins, magazines and local newspapers, pamphlets, public notices, artistic and theatrical programs, government reports and studies, and many other types of printed matter relating to Wilton history. The topical scope of the collection is wide, ranging from the artistic catalogs of Kenneth Lynch, a noted local metalsmith, through civically minded League of Women Voters calendars, and recreational ephemera, such as horse show programs. The earliest dated original items are from the mid-1800s, although later reprints of earlier materials are included. The bulk of the collection was produced in the twentieth century. New materials continue to be added, making this collection a major repository of Wilton's more recent history.
Arrangement
Collection materials are in folders arranged alphabetically in filing cabinet drawers.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Churches.; Cemeteries.; Clubs.; Borglum, Solon Hannibal, 1868-1922.; Browne, Dik.; Gilbert and Bennett Manufacturing Company.; Housing.; League of Women Voters of Wilton, Connecticut.; Local government.; Lynch, Kenneth, 1904-.; Manning, Jane Elizabeth, approximately 1813-1908.; Mutrux, Robert.; Parks; Proctor, Alexander Phimister, 1860-1950.; Smith, E. Boyd (Elmer Boyd), 1860-1943.; Schools.; Societies.; Student writing.; Taxes.; Town planning.; Van Hoosear, David Hermon, 1844-.; War.; Weir Farm National Historic Site (Conn.).; WPA.; Zoning.
Related Collections
Those researching most non-genealogical topics in the Wilton Historical Society Printed Matter Collection in the Wilton History Room should additionally consult the Wilton Historical Information and Manuscripts collections.
Separated Material
Select additional printed matter may be found in the Wilton Historical Society Museum.
- 1. Art and artists
  - Artists and cartoonists by name
    - Borglum, Solon, undated; See MC 6-9, Borglum Scrapbook. (Cabinet 8, Folder 151)
    - Browne, Dik and Chase, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 171b)
    - Lynch, Kenneth - Catalogs and miscellaneous printed material, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 341a; 542)
    - Lynch, Kenneth - Garden ornament book, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 341b)
    - Proctor, Alexander Phimister, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 153a)
    - Smith, E. Boyd - "The Farm Book" - Posters, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 152a)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Cos Cob artists program, undated; Includes E. Boyd Smith. (Cabinet 8, Folder 152b)
    - "Who's Who at the Village Luncheonette, a sketch book by Balazs", 1990 (Cabinet 8, Folder 153b)
    - Wilton artists - Exhibition programs, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 155)
    - WPA restoration project, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 154)
- 2. Churches
  - Miscellaneous
    - Congregational churches in Connecticut, 1944; Includes a history of Wilton Parish and Reverend John Gaylord Davenport. (Cabinet 8, Folder 211aa)
    - Directory of Protestant churches, 1933 (Cabinet 8, Folder 211a)
    - First Congregational Church on the Green, Norwalk, 1955 (Cabinet 8, Folder 211ab)
    - Georgetown Methodist Church, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 211b)
    - Our Lady of Fatima, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 212)
    - Sermons, 1811 (Cabinet 8, Folder 476b)
    - St. Paul’s on the Green - Reverend Jeremiah Learning - Biographical sketch, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 214fa)
    - Sunday school cards, undated; Belonged to John M. Belden. (Cabinet 8, Folder 502)
    - Wilton Presbyterian Church - Ministers' memoirs, 1961-1987; "Not Without Laughter" by Stephen Jacobs (1980-1987) and "Random Memories" by W. Stewart MacColl (1961-1979). (Cabinet 8, Folder 218)
  - St. Matthew's Episcopal Church
    - "Cooperative Venture in Faith", 1968 (Cabinet 8, Folder 214a)
    - Directory, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 214e)
    - Newsletters - "The Vine", undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 214c)
    - Parish history - "150th Anniversary”, 1802-1952 (Cabinet 8, Folder 214d)
    - Programs, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 214f)
    - White, Mary Davenport - Semi-centennial historical paper, 1862 (Cabinet 8, Folder 214b)
  - Wilton Congregational Church
    - 175th Anniversary Program, 1901 (Cabinet 8, Folder 216a)
    - 200th Anniversary Program, 1926 (Cabinet 8, Folder 216b)
    - 225th Anniversary Program, 1951 (Cabinet 8, Folder 217a)
    - 275th Anniversary Program, 2001 (Cabinet 8, Folder 217b)
    - Annual reports, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 214g)
    - By-laws, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 214h)
    - Manual, 1726-1904 (Cabinet 8, Folder 215b)
    - Membership directory, 1976 (Cabinet 8, Folder 215c)
    - Miscellaneous programs, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 215d)
    - Olmstead, Marion - "Wilton Parish: A Historical Sketch, 1726-1800", 1900 (Cabinet 8, Folder 217 c)
    - Olmstead, Mrs. Edward - "Eighty Years of Women's Work", 1916; On the Ladies Home Missionary Society and the Women's Fellowship. (Cabinet 8, Folder 215a)
    - "Open Door" letters, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 215ca)
    - Pamphlets, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 215cb)
    - Reverend Hanson - Ordination sermon, 1942 (Cabinet 8, Folder 217ba)
    - Women’s Fellowship, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 217ca)
  - Zion's Hill Methodist Church
    - Christian education - Sunday school, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 219b)
    - History, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 219a)
    - Mother-daughter banquet, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 219c)
    - Programs, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 219d)
    - Women’s Society of Christian Service, 1962-1978 (Cabinet 8, Folder 219e)
- 3. Civic and social organizations
  - League of Women Voters
    - Calendars, 1972-1986; File 332 covers 1972-1985; file 334 coverage begins from 1986. (Cabinet 8, Folder 332, 334)
    - Handbooks, 1943-1970; File 336 covers 1943-1965; file 338 coverage begins from 1970. (Cabinet 8, Folder 336, 338)
    - League of Women Voters, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 230)
  - Miscellaneous
    - American Legion, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 220)
    - Cannon Grange, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 222)
    - Cannon Grange - Agricultural fair program, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 170c)
    - Masonic lodges, 1886-1896 (Cabinet 8, Folder 240)
    - PTA Choral Club - Program, 1947 (Cabinet 8, Folder 242)
    - Social Club of South Wilton - Minutes, 1923-1933 (Cabinet 8, Folder 245)
    - Teen Center, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 503aa)
    - Wilton Arts Council, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 250)
    - Wilton Garden Club, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 253)
    - Wilton Land Trust, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 255)
  - Wilton Family Y
    - Community celebration, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 251aa)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 251a)
    - Wilton Y - Newsletters, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 252)
    - Yahoos, 1993-1994 (Cabinet 8, Folder 251b)
  - Wilton Newcomers Club
    - Directories, 1976-1999; File 258 covers 1976-1988; file 259 coverage covers 1984-1999. (Cabinet 8, Folder 258, 259)
    - Programs, 1969 (Cabinet 8, Folder 265)
- 4. Miscellaneous by topic
  - Architects and architecture
    - Architecture - Wilton, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 145)
    - Mutrux, Robert, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 144)
  - Business and industry
    - Business brochures, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 158)
    - Business cards, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 160)
    - Gilbert and Bennett Manufacturing Company - Bicentennial, 1976 (Cabinet 8, Folder 317a)
    - Gilbert and Bennett Manufacturing Company - Flood report, 1955 (Cabinet 8, Folder 317aa)
    - Gilbert and Bennett Manufacturing Company - History, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 317ab)
    - Gregory Brothers - Invoices, 1933; See also Perry. (Cabinet 8, Folder 324b)
    - Construction Industry, Trades, General Contractors and Sub-Contractors - Directory, undated; Mid-20th century. (Cabinet 8, Folder 329c)
    - Miscellaneous businesses, undated; File 541 includes the Cannondale Corporation. (Cabinet 8, Folder 540, 541)
    - Wilton business directory, 1997-2000 (Cabinet 8, Folder 585)
    - Wilton Supply Company, Inc. - Woodwork services catalog, 1958 (Cabinet 8, Folder 591)
  - Disasters
    - Floods, 1955; Disasters of August and October, 1955. (Cabinet 8, Folder 316)
    - Hurricane, 1938 (Cabinet 8, Folder 329b)
    - Hurricane and flood, 1928; Disaster of September 21, 1928. (Cabinet 8, Folder 308b)
    - Ice storm, 1940; Disaster of March, 1940. (Cabinet 8, Folder 308c)
    - The Big Storm - Album, undated-1950; Disaster of November 25, 1950. (Cabinet 8, Folder 308d)
  - Health and medical facilities
    - Newsletters, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 360)
    - Public health, 1947-1948 (Cabinet 8, Folder 410a)
    - Public health programs - Wilton, 1973 (Cabinet 8, Folder 410b)
    - Visiting nurses, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 521e)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Authors, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 530)
    - Cannon Crossing, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 170b)
    - Cemetery Inscriptions - East Norwalk, 1892; See also "Gravestones." (Cabinet 8, Folder 200)
    - Cross, Samuel - "Home Rule", 1984 (Cabinet 8, Folder 340a)
    - Currency - "A Lecture by Abel Whitlock", 1874 (Cabinet 8, Folder 305)
    - Dibner and Bundy Libraries, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 308aa)
    - Envelopes and stamps, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 310)
    - Fashions and patterns, 1883 (Cabinet 8, Folder 312)
    - Geology and hydrology of Wilton, 1974 (Cabinet 8, Folder 511c)
    - Gravestones - "A Grave Business", undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 324a)
    - Lambert, Eva Ogden - Writings, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 330)
    - Manning, Jane Elizabeth - Scholarship by Quincy D. Newell, 2013; A journal article and a book chapter by Quincy D. Newell on Jane Elizabeth Manning. (Cabinet 8, Folder 349b)
    - Memorials, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 350a)
    - Perry, Albert Gregory - "Life Lessons", 2004 (Cabinet 8, Folder 381)
    - Railroad ticket - Shipping receipt, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 415)
    - Recipe book, 1877; Booklet of printed recipes; full title is Ransom's family receipt [sic] book. (Cabinet 8, Folder 418)
    - Samuelson Anthology of Poetry, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 474b)
    - Signers of the Mayflower Compact - Brewster records, 1902 (Cabinet 8, Folder 326)
    - Souvenir - Views from the Singer Building, New York City, 1910 (Cabinet 8, Folder 478a)
    - Suffragists, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 522aa)
    - Abbott, A. C. - Comstock House - Time book, 1931-1932 (Cabinet 8, Folder 508a)
    - Van Hoosear, David Hermon - "Van Hoosear Genealogy", 1902 (Cabinet 8, Folder 521c)
  - Weir Farm National Historic Site
    - Brochures and cards, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 524a)
    - Cultural landscape report, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 524b)
    - Educational materials, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 525a)
    - Exhibits and visiting artists, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 525b)
    - Management plan, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 526a)
    - National Park Service - Newsletters, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 526b)
    - Weir Farm News, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 527a)
- 5. Miscellaneous by type
  - Almanacs
    - Christian Almanac, 1834-1841 (Cabinet 8, Folder 104)
    - Connecticut Register and Almanack, 1805-1833 (Cabinet 8, Folder 105)
    - Middlebrook's Almanack, 1826-1918; File 120 covers 1826-1883; file 125 covers 1876-1899; file 130 covers 1900-1909; file 135 covers 1910-1918. (Cabinet 8, Folder 120, 125, 130, 135)
    - Miscellaneous, 1807-1959 (Cabinet 8, Folder 140)
    - The Farmer's Almanack, 1794-1839 (Cabinet 8, Folder 110)
  - Calendars
    - Miscellaneous, 1965-1968; See also photographs. (Cabinet 8, Folder 170a)
    - Ridgefield Bank, 1996-2005; File 170aa covers 1996-2000; file 170ab covers 2001-2004; file 170ac covers 2005 and beyond. (Cabinet 8, Folder 170aa, 170ab, 170ac)
    - Yankee Heritage District - Calendar of events, undated; Norwalk and Wilton. (Cabinet 8, Folder 165)
  - Catalogs
    - Fruit and ornamental trees, 1841 (Cabinet 8, Folder 172)
  - Greeting, post, and picture cards
    - Christmas cards, undated; See also PHO, Congregational Church Christmas cards. (Cabinet 8, Folder 210)
    - Picture cards, undated; Belonged to John Belden as a child. (Cabinet 8, Folder 382)
    - Post cards, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 400)
  - Magazines
    - Frank Leslie's Boy's and Girl's Weekly, 1869; Published by Frank Leslie. (Cabinet 8, Folder 411)
    - The Bellman, 1911-1913 (Cabinet 8, Folder 413)
    - The Century Magazine, Scribner's Monthly - Magazine club members list, 1881-1894 (Cabinet 8, Folder 349a)
    - The Mark: The Magazine of Fairfield County, 1966 (Cabinet 8, Folder 414e)
    - The Weasel, 1875-1903; Published by Richard Fitch (1901-1903) and Arthur Fitch (1875). (Cabinet 8, Folder 412)
    - The Wiltonian, 1962-1967; File 414a covers 1962-1963; file 414b covers 1964-1965; file 414c covers 1966-1967. (Cabinet 8, Folder 414a, 414b, 414c)
    - Town House Trumpet, 1893; Published by Richard Fitch. (Cabinet 8, Folder 414d)
  - Maps
    - Fairfield County, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 342)
    - New York, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 344)
    - Wilton, 1975-1981 (Cabinet 8, Folder 348)
  - Public notices and advertisements
    - Advertisement, 1884 (Cabinet 8, Folder 100)
    - Assessors’ notices, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 354)
    - Auction notices, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 351)
    - Republican Party notices, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 355)
    - Town contract notices, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 352)
    - Town meeting notices, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 353)
  - Telephone directories
    - Telephone directory - Connecticut, 1902 (Cabinet 8, Folder 503c)
    - Telephone directory - Wilton, 1951 (Cabinet 8, Folder 503b)
- 6. Entertainment, Recreation, and Sports
  - Horse Shows
    - Correspondence and descriptions, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 431c)
    - Programs, 1926-1953; File 431a covers 1926-1938; file 431b covers 1941-1953. (Cabinet 8, Folder 431a, 431b)
    - Thomas, Ada Maude - Excerpts from "Mrs. T.", undated; Horse Show memories. (Cabinet 8, Folder 431d)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Camps, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 420)
    - Commission, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 421)
    - Dance, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 308a)
    - Field Day - Notice, 1928 (Cabinet 8, Folder 425)
    - "Going Places", undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 423)
    - Parks and recreation - Programs, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 428)
    - Wilton Golf Club, 1898 (Cabinet 8, Folder 430)
  - Music
    - Brubeck Concert - Programs, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 350c)
    - Cannon Men's Chorus - Sheet music, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 171a)
    - Municipal facilities feasibility study, 1979 (Cabinet 8, Folder 350ab)
    - Silvermine Festival - Program, 1938 (Cabinet 8, Folder 350b)
    - Wilton PTA Choral Club, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 350aba)
  - Theatricals
    - Garrick Club, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 504)
    - George Washington Pageant - Program, 1932 (Cabinet 8, Folder 506)
    - Miscellaneous programs, 1921 (Cabinet 8, Folder 505a)
    - "Wilton Dearest" - Program, 1990 (Cabinet 8, Folder 507)
    - Wilton Schools, "Alice in Wonderland" - Program, 1933 (Cabinet 8, Folder 505b)
    - Wilton Student Productions - Miscellaneous, 1980s (Cabinet 8, Folder 505c)
  - Wilton Riding Club
    - Bylaws, 1941-2001 (Cabinet 8, Folder 569)
    - Directories, 1941-1992; Files contain directories for (a) 1941-1953, (b) 1958-1967, (c) 1968-1977, (d) 1978-1984, (e) 1985-1992. (Cabinet 8, Folder 570a, 570b, 570c, 570d, 570e)
- 7. Schools and education
  - Miscellaneous by school
    - Bald Hill School, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 444)
    - Comstock School, 1965 (Cabinet 8, Folder 453)
    - English and Classical School of Norwalk, 1847 (Cabinet 8, Folder 456a)
    - Evaluation of Wilton Junior High, 1956 (Cabinet 8, Folder 456aaa)
    - "Miller Milestone", 1981-1983 (Cabinet 8, Folder 462c)
    - Miller School - Dedication and open house, 1967 (Cabinet 8, Folder 462a)
    - Miller School - Handbooks and directories, 1,985-1987 (Cabinet 8, Folder 462b)
    - Norwalk High School - Commencement program, 1913 (Cabinet 8, Folder 474a)
    - Ogden's School for Young Girls., undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 463a)
    - Wilton Academy, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 466)
  - Miscellaneous by topic
    - ABC (A Better Chance) - Newsletter, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 90)
    - Board of Education - Newsletters and stationery, 1958-1962 (Cabinet 8, Folder 445)
    - College bulletins, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 300)
    - Commencement - Eighth grade, 1929-1939 (Cabinet 8, Folder 452b)
    - Commencement exercises and dedications, 1951 (Cabinet 8, Folder 455)
    - Curriculum of the Wilton Public Schools, 1976-1977 (Cabinet 8, Folder 454)
    - Enrollments, 1959-2010 (Cabinet 8, Folder 456aa)
    - History of the Wilton School System, 1726-1935 (Cabinet 8, Folder 456b)
    - How to Make the Most of Your Schools, 1949 (Cabinet 8, Folder 457)
    - Kindergarten - Report cards, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 461a)
    - Martin, Helen - Tribute, 2000 (Cabinet 8, Folder 461b)
    - Personnel directories, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 463b)
    - PTA, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 405)
    - Public education in Wilton, 1960 (Cabinet 8, Folder 465a)
    - School Study Committee on Merit Rating, 1953 (Cabinet 8, Folder 465aa)
    - Strategic School Profile, 1991-1992 (Cabinet 8, Folder 464a)
    - Sturges, Dell - "Little Red Schoolhouse", undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 461aa)
    - Testing report, 1995-1996 (Cabinet 8, Folder 465b)
    - "These are your Schools", 1945 (Cabinet 8, Folder 465c)
    - Values committee report, 1966 (Cabinet 8, Folder 465d)
    - What's Different About a Junior-High School?, 1950 (Cabinet 8, Folder 460a)
    - Wilton Public Schools - Profile, 1979-1991 (Cabinet 8, Folder 464b)
  - School building programs
    - Cafeterias, 1961 (Cabinet 8, Folder 452a)
    - Long range building program, 1965 (Cabinet 8, Folder 446)
    - Long range school building plan, 1955 (Cabinet 8, Folder 447)
    - Memorandum - School building program, 1952 (Cabinet 8, Folder 448a)
    - Proposed new Junior-Senior High School for Wilton, 1956 (Cabinet 8, Folder 459)
    - School facilities report, 1991 (Cabinet 8, Folder 448aa)
    - Study of school building needs, 1948 (Cabinet 8, Folder 465ab)
    - Study of school building needs, 1948 (Cabinet 8, Folder 448b)
    - Wilton, Connecticut Builds a School, 1951 (Cabinet 8, Folder 449)
  - Wilton High School
    - A New High School for Wilton, 1960 (Cabinet 8, Folder 467)
    - Academic profile, 1963 (Cabinet 8, Folder 468)
    - Building Committee - Report, 1961 (Cabinet 8, Folder 468a)
    - Dedication, 1972 (Cabinet 8, Folder 469)
    - Graduation programs, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 470)
    - Handbook, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 471a)
    - Program of Educational and Community Requirements (Engelhardt, etc.), 1959 (Cabinet 8, Folder 471b)
    - Report on the Establishing of a Regional High School for Weston, Redding, and Wilton, 1944 (Cabinet 8, Folder 472)
    - Resource Center, circa1975 (Cabinet 8, Folder 473a)
    - Reunion memoirs - Class of 1959, 1999 (Cabinet 8, Folder 473b)
- Writings by students
  - Center School
    - Connecticut tercentary, 1635-1935 (Cabinet 8, Folder 478b)
    - "Wilton Town", 1726-1935 (Cabinet 8, Folder 478b)
  - Miscellaneous by school
    - Cider Mill - Writings, 1974-1976 (Cabinet 8, Folder 478d)
    - Middlebrook - Writings, 1975-1979 (Cabinet 8, Folder 478e)
    - Miller-Driscoll - Writings, 1972-1973 (Cabinet 8, Folder 478f)
    - Wilton Elementary - Writings, 1935-1960; File 480 covers 1935-1956; file 481 covers 1957-1959; file 482 covers 1960. (Cabinet 8, Folder 480, 481, 482)
    - Wilton Junior High - Writings, 1970-1985 (Cabinet 8, Folder 490)
  - Staples High School
    - Landmark "Buzz", 1996 (Cabinet 8, Folder 479c)
    - School paper - "Inklings", undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 479b)
    - Wilton Students, 1947-1949 (Cabinet 8, Folder 479)
  - Wilton High School
    - Avant Garde, 1992 (Cabinet 8, Folder 501a)
    - Lunacy, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 501b)
    - Wilton High School, 1965-1977 (Cabinet 8, Folder 500)
- 8. Town of Wilton
  - Celebrations and observances
    - 250th anniversary and founding of Norwalk, 1901 (Cabinet 8, Folder 177)
    - Celebrate Wilton Day, 1994 (Cabinet 8, Folder 509a)
    - Celebration of the bicentennial of the birth of George Washington, 1832 (Cabinet 8, Folder 178)
    - Dedication of Town Hall, 1931 (Cabinet 8, Folder 180)
    - Dedication on new Town Hall, 1931; Dated February 14, 1931. (Cabinet 8, Folder 509d)
    - Go Green Festival, undated (Cabinet 8, Folder 546)
    - Raising of the flag, 1917 (Cabinet 8, Folder 185)
    - Tercentary, 1935-1936 (Cabinet 8, Folder 190)